There are two main approaches that I will try:

1. Use POS and parsing tree to extract possible name entities. It probably involves some prebuilt Libraries/Packages.

2. Train LSTM-RNN/CNN, either at word level or character level.

Issues that might be hard to cope with:
It is very likely that we recognize many name entities that we are not interested in, such as journalist's name, some governor's name, etc.



>>> Ian Ma, Oct 10 - Oct 18, 2019:

Repos:
Model: https://github.com/guillaumegenthial/tf_ner
Dataset: https://github.com/synalp/NER
Paper: End-to-end Sequence Labeling via Bi-directional LSTM-CNNs-CRF (https://arxiv.org/abs/1603.01354)

--- Results: (Relatively short training, ~ 30 min, training accuracy: ~0.97, precision: ~0.89)

Labels:
ORG: Organization
LOC: Location
MISC: everything other than the first 3 classes

1. 002fcbe4-503c-400d-8cc0-77a395570ade.txt
preds: O    O     O  B-ORG I-ORG O   O   O           O  O   B-ORG   I-ORG   I-ORG      I-ORG  O B-ORG      I-ORG    O  O   B-MISC   I-MISC I-MISC  O        B-PER   I-PER   O       O    O     O   O     O    O  O  O    O  O      O      O        O   O          O  B-MISC   O         O         O    O    O    O      O  O   O      O        O        O       O       O   O

--- Observations:
1. Works poorly when the organizations's name starts with a number. E.g., 1 Mechanised Division of the Nigerian Army (Result 3.)
2. This model only have lables: PER ORG LOC MISC (MISC is for everything other than the first 3 classes). Therefore, it cannot classify titles, ranks, etc. The dataset is CONLL2003. If we switch to our dataset, it might improve.
